So as you know, for now, each sector has a sector trailer, and sector trailer is a block through
which you can access data, right?
So access conditions are stored in sector trailer, the key A and key B and the access bits.
All these things are in sector trailer, right?
So right now we will see the access condition of data blocks through sector trailer.
So over here you can see C1, C2, C3 these are access bits.
Now I told you in my previous videos there are four access bits in each sector trailer, but we use
only three access bits.
The first three access bits C1, c2, c3 are the name given for for just for reference right now, but
we only use the first three bits.
So suppose the access bits are 000 in in any sector trailer, the three access bits, the first three
access bits are 000.
Now what you can do if the access bits are 000.
So over here is the access condition.
Now this is this access condition is for data block.
Similarly, we will see the access condition of sector trailer as well with the access bits.
Right.
So this access bit controls the access condition of data blocks as well as access condition of sector
as well.
So over here you can see the first three bits are zero.
So if the first three bits are zero, we can read data block with key A or key B, and we can write
data block any data block in a specific sector trailer with key A and key B, and we can increment the
data block with key A or key B, and we can also decrement data with key A or key B, right?
So this is the Or symbol over here.
So we can read either with key, key A or key B, both will work over here just fine.
And we can write with key A or key B that will also work fine.
And increment and decrement are the special operations which are used in value blocks.
Now value blocks are also data blocks.
We will go into value blocks in our next video, but just remember that value blocks are related to
integers and in integers, either you can increment the integer or you can decrement the integer.
So that is the concept for the value blocks, which we will go through the concept in further detail
in our next video.
But right now, just remember that we can also increment with key A or key B and we can decrement with
key A or key B as well, right?
If the condition is 000.
Now, this condition is also known as transport configuration.
Transport configuration is a default configuration on which your card comes.
So whenever you purchase a new card, it will be on a transport configuration.
And so you can easily read or write data.
Now the second condition is 010 when the middle bit is on one.
You can read with key A or key B.
You can read any data block with key A or key B, but you can never write.
If the condition access condition is this and you can never increment and you can never decrement.
Similarly, if the access bits are 100, you can read with key A or key B, but you can only write with
key B and you can never increment or never decrement.
If the access bits are 110, then you can read with key A or key B and you can write with key B and
you can increment with key B and you can decrement with key A or key B.
Similarly, if the access bits are 001, you can read with key A or key B, but you can never write,
never increment, and you can decrement with key A or key B.
Similarly, if the excess bits are 011, you can only read with key B and you can write with key B and
never increment and never decrement.
And if the excess bits are 101, you can read with key B Never write, never increment or never decrement.
Similarly, if the excess bits are 111 so you can do nothing on this access block.
You can never read, never write, never increment or never decrement.
This is a special case where you want to block certain data blocks and you never want to change that.
Block so you can apply this condition over there.
So this is the access condition for data block.
And now we will see the access condition for sector trailer.
So similarly, sector trailer is also controlled with access bits.
The first three access bit of any sector trailer.
So if the access bits are 000, you can never read.
Over here you can see that in key A you can never read.
Right.
So this is the condition for key.
So you can never read Qi.
So this Qi must be on on any reader.
This is this.
I'm just giving you just a concept right now.
But this concept will be clear in the future.
Videos.
But just it has come over here.
So I'm just giving you just a concept over here so you can not read Qi a in any case.
Right?
So Qi A must be on the reader as well as on the card, right?
So whenever we create any application and we want to read data or write data with Qi, Qi must be present
on the reader side.
So this concept will be much clearer in our future videos.
But right now, just you have to remember the access condition of Sector Trailer.
So let's just move into our sector trailer.
So, so if the access bits are 000.
Right?
So you can read.
Sorry, you can never read key, but you can write key A Right.
So if the access bits are 000, you can never read key A but you can write key and you can access access
bits with key A But you can never write.
Exhibits on condition of 000.
Right.
And you can read key with key as well as.
Key B with key.
Right.
So in the next condition, if the condition is 010, you can still never read Kia and never ride Kia.
But you can access access with Kia and never write on access bits on this condition.
You can read B as well and you can never write on KB.
When the condition is 010.
If the condition is 100, then you can never read key as before, but you can write with key B on key
A and you can access access bit with key A or key B, You can use any of these keys, but you can never
write on access bits and you can never read key B.
And you can write with key on.
Right.
So these concepts are a little complicated, but this chart will help you a lot.
So you have to just remember this chart and whenever the condition is one one excess bits are 110.
You can never read key.
You can never write key.
You can use excess bits.
You can use key or key to access access bits, but you can never write on excess bits, you can never
read on key or you can never write on key B If the condition is 001, you can never write on key.
You can read key.
Sorry, you can never read key.
But you can write Kia with Kia and you can access access built with Kia.
You can also write access bits with Kia.
You can write so you can read key with Kia and you can also write key with Kia over here.
And when the excess bits are 011 you can never read.
You can write key with key B, you can access excess bits with key A or key B and you can write excess
bit.
With key B, you can never read key B and you can write with key B similarly.
101.
And one one 1 in 1, one one.
You can never read.
You can never write a you can access access bits with key A or key B, but you can never write, never
read.
So you have to go through this table more than once.
There are two conditions access conditions, one for a data block and one for sector trailer.
So you have to master these things before proceeding into further videos.
So just remember these concepts for the future videos.